Andrew Onoruese

Junior Full-Stack Developer

💌 onorueserukky4@gmail.com 📞 +4917684855255 🔮 Elssholzstrasse 20, 10781 Berlin 🙀 LinkedIn

PROFILE

A junior full-stack developer with 3+ years of experience working as a front-end Developer with demonstrated ability to collaborate with Junior and senior developers. I enjoy working in a cross-functional team, writing clean and reusable code, and ensuring workloads are efficiently redirected to bottlenecks. I am enthusiastic about software development and adapt quickly to new technologies, constantly looking to educate myself and acquire new skills. I always want to be involved in the entire software lifecycle, from planning to implementation to live deployment.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer

Stallion Tech (Hybrid)

11/2019 - 02/2022 Uyo, Nigeria

- Maintained 15+ web pages under the direction of the UX manager and development team.
- Created and designed modules using semantic HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React to create responsive web pages and web applications that work across desktops, mobile devices, and 10+ other devices.
- Tested website performance and experience using Google Lighthouse.
- Actively participated in code reviews.
- Worked with other developers in an agile working environment.
- Performed unit testing and integration testing and deployed them for use.

Front-End Developer Intern

Decagon Institute (on-site)

01/2019 - 08/2019 Lagos, Nigeria

- Assisted the development team in maintaining 7 websites.
- Implemented front-end tools and CSS preprocessors to meet project requirements for the creation of 11 new web pages.
- Conducted research and helped in the business application areas with attempts to scope out new business, which led to the acquisition of 7 new clients, boosting profits by 10%.
- I collaborated with other interns and developers to create multiple web pages using HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, and Vue.js
- Used storybook for development, testing, and documentation of web pages and web applications.

EDUCATION

Masters engineering management

IU International University of Applied Sciences Berlin

04/2022 - 06/2023Berlin, Germany

MY PORTFOLIO

Portfolio &

SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, PHP, Node.js, Kubernetes, Google lighthouse, Git, Jira
- Adaptability, Effective communication, Problem solving, Team player, Receptive to feedbacks, Attention to details and trends, Active listener

LANGUAGES

English German \bullet

COURSES

The complete 2023 web development bootcamp (Dr. Angela yu) 🔗

2023 – present

Udemy

Duration of course: 65 hours + Progress level: 80% complete.

CERTIFICATES

• Front-end web development bootcamp 2021 ⊗

 Agile and Scrum: From Agile mindset to Scrum implementation ∂

INTERESTS

Puzzle solving | **Gaming** | **Cooking** | **Surfing the net** (Passion for cutting edge technology)

REFERENCES

Available upon request